Don't take the video lightly, Guy, it's a very
important video. A small mistake can
lead to your claim being rejected, and
you may have to bear a huge loss. Hello
Guy, no matter which EV two-wheeler you have,
you must have taken insurance for your vehicle, the
price of which ranges from Rs. 8,000
to Rs. 10,000. So,
how can this Rs. 8,000 to Rs. 10,000 benefit you in the future?
How can you avail its benefits? If an
accident happens, how can you make a claim,
and what should you keep in mind while making a claim so
that your
claim is not rejected? Yes Guy, if
your claim is rejected once, you will have to
pay the entire accident cost from your own pocket, which can prove to be very costly for you.
So Guy, in this video, we will
learn how to make a two-wheeler insurance claim.
What is the process if you have booked the vehicle offline, and if you have
booked the vehicle online, for example, if
Ola users are booking online,
what is their process? These are the procedures for both these processes.
I will talk about this, do
not take this video lightly guys, it is a very important
video, due to a small mistake your
claim can be rejected and you may have to
suffer a huge loss, so without
wasting any time let's start the video,
before that I want to tell you about one more amazing thing
which is our
Electric Story Ka
Guys 80, all the users
solve the problem by discussing among themselves, we have
separate AV group for every state, if you have bought it
from LA, then you go to the showroom, in this case the
showroom people will help you completely, but
if you have bought the vehicle online, which I have already bought, then
you have to first call LA customer care and
register a complaint,
after that you have to take that complaint number and
call the insurance company yourself
and then explain your accident and make an
insurance claim,
when you complain on the phone,
then they send you a link
where you have to send the photo of your scooters, all the
broken parts
You have to send the same photo to them.
After that, you get a
verification call. See, guys, this is where the
whole game can change. This call
mostly
comes from the headquarter of the insurance company, which can be
anywhere like Delhi, Mumbai or Hyderabad.
This call is a very
important call because they record this
conversation. They
will not tell you that they are recording it, but they do
record it, and
whatever you say in this conversation will be
considered for your final claim. Now
see where the mistake happens. When you get a
call from the company, they will ask for your name. Then they will ask for the
address of the place where your car met with the accident.
After that, they will also ask who was driving the car.
See, guys, the documents of the person who drives the car are
also required.
They will ask you for a valid license in his name, but
you will not be told this on the phone. At this
time, they will only ask for your name. Suppose
you said that my younger brother
is driving the car, as per the rules, the person who is in your blood
relation.  If those people are driving the car, then
you will get the claim. Yes, if
any of your friends is driving the car, then you will
not get the claim. So if you say that
my younger brother was driving the car, then remember
that he should have a valid license.
If you are not able to provide that license, then
your claim will be rejected. So keep this thing in
mind that the person whose name you take should have
a valid license. Suppose
if the younger brother is driving the car but he does
not have a license, then you should not take his name at all.
You should take the name of a blood relation
whose documents you can provide, who has a
valid license. Understood? Yes, and
now this will only happen with blood relations.
If the friend is driving the car and he has a
license, then also this claim will be rejected.
For this,
you have to keep this thing very clear during phone verification. If
I talk about the members of my West Bengal group, then
their claim has been
rejected because the
person who was driving the car at the time of the accident did
not have a valid license. Yes,
his guy.  I had a learner's license and
learner's license will not suffice. Look guys, there is no
big hassle in getting the claim approved.
You just have to ensure
that you are able to provide the license and
if you don't have a license, then
mention the name of someone who has a license and is your
blood relation. Look guys, the
insurance company does not do much verification whether
you are telling the truth or not,
they just want the license of the person who was
driving the car. Did you understand? Then
after the tele-verification is complete, they will
sign a local person from their company
who will communicate with you. He will
come to you, inspect your car, take a photo again.
After that, after coordinating with the service center, the
insurance person will cover all your expenses for the car. I hope you
understood what I wanted to tell you. Still, if you have any question, then
come to the group and discuss.
To join the group,
you simply have to write in the comments. You will be given the join link.
Next, any EV video related matter  I
request if you like anything then
please tell me in the comments, I read all the comments
and try my best to reply to everyone, so that's all for
this video, see you
in the next video.